Finding Aid for Pond Family Papers 1841-1939
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Visual materials
  - Cased photographs
    - Daguerreotypes
      - Family group, good condition, nice case, 4.5"x3.5" (Box 8)
        [no. 8]
      - Woman with open book, good condition, no clasps, 4.5"x3.5" (Box 8)
        [no. 9]
      - Stern man with cane, medium good condition, 4.5"x3.5" (Box 8)
        [no. 10]
      - Man with checkered vest, broken binding, 4.5"x3.5" (Box 8)
        [no. 11]
      - Man with hand on book, broken case inlaid with mother-of-pearl, 3"x3.5" (Box 8)
        [no. 12]
    - Ambrotypes
      - Girl with locks, good condition, 3"x3.5" (Box 8)
        [no. 13]
      - Man with gold tie-pin, good condition, 3"x3.5" (Box 8)
        [no. 14]
      - Baby, poor condition, broken, exposed, scratched, 3"x3.5" (Box 8)
        [no. 15]
      - Boy by chair, poor condition, out of case, scratched, 5.5"x4" (Box 8)
        [no. 16]
      - Mary Allen Pond, out of case but sealed, 2.75"x2.75" (Box 8)
        [no. 17]
      - Mary Allen Pond with daughter, out of case, 4.25"x3.5" (Box 8)
        [no. 18]
      - Elihu Pond, Out of case, cracked, 2.75"x3.5" (Box 8)
        [no. 19]
  - Albums
    - Leather-bound family albums, 4 volumes (Box 9)
    - Small red cloth-bound album with 6 photographs (Box 9)
    - Small red cloth-bound album marked "Irving K. Pond--Sketches", 5"x7" (Box 9)
      includes portraits, caricatures, and sketches of Chicago
    - Larger red cloth-bound album marked "Irving K. Pond--Sketches", 6"x9" (Box 9)
      includes water colors of California, Arizona, New Mexico, Chicago, the Columbian Exposition, Wisconsin, and Ann Arbor scenes
  - Etching plates
    - 1880, 2 items (Box 9)
  - Architectural drawings
    - China
      - Shanghai. United States Building, Burlingame Ward Memorial 1914 (Map-case 2)
    - Illinois
      - Chicago
        - Chicago Tribune Building proposal, 1 sheets (Map-case 2)
        - Gads Hill Center (Map-case 2)
        - Passenger Terminal proposal 1913 (Box 10)
        - Polish National Alliance Building (Box 10)
        - Pond and Pond Offices 1909, 1926 (Box 10)
        - State Street Improvements (Box 10)
      - Evanston
        - James T. Hatfield Residence addition (Box 10)
        - James T. Hatfield Residence, addition, 5 sheets (Map-case 2)
      - Wheaton
        - American Theosophical Society Building (Map-case 2)
        - American Theosophical Society Building 1925 (Box 10)
    - Kansas
      - Lawrence. Kansas University Memorial Union 1924 (Map-case 2)
    - Michigan
      - Ann Arbor
        - Campus plot plan undated, 1 blueprints (Map-case 2)
        - Hill Auditorium 1911, 2 blueprints (Map-case 2)
        - Michigan League 1929, 1930, undated (Map-case 2)
          site plan and details. Blueprints
        - Michigan League 1927, 38 volumes bound sheets; Ink on linen (Map-case 1)
          elevations, sections, details, footing plan, floor plans, roof plan, mechanical plans, tree plan, site plans.
        - Michigan Union 1916-1917, 100 bound sheets 60 for 1916; 40 for 1917 Ink on linen (Map-case 1)
          site plan, foundation plans, floor plans, elevations, sections, details, framing plans and details, heading and ventilating plans, mechanical, structural, and electrical schedules
        - Michigan Union 1917, 1929, Ink on linen (Map-case 2)
          (details, elevations, and floor plans showing addition; also 1 rendering watercolor; donor no. 260)
        - Physical Laboratory proposed addition undated, 4 sheets (Map-case 2)
          elevations, sections, floor plans; Blueprints
        - Pond Monument, Forest Hill Cemetery 1930 (Box 10)
        - Press Building [Student Publications Building] 1930, 14 volumes bound sheets; Ink on linen (Map-case 1)
          floor plans, roof plan, elevations, sections, details
        - School of Music proposal 1929 (Box 10)
        - School of Religion proposal 1923 (Map-case 2)
          1 floor plan. Blueprint
        - University Club proposal 1931 (Map-case 2)
          floor plans and elevations. Blueprints
      - Detroit
        - Detroit Opera House 1897 (Map-case 2)
      - Port Huron
        - Port Huron General Hospital, details for Power House, 8 sheets (Map-case 2)
      - St. Joseph
        - Royalton ,Hadleigh Hill, Dickinson Residence, 8 sheets (Map-case 2)
    - Oregon
      - Hood River
        - A. Cox Residence, 9 items (Map-case 2)
    - Washington
      - Seattle
        - Washington With the Sword of State, statue (Map-case 2)
        - Washington With the Sword of State, statue (Box 10)
    - Washington, D.C
      - Roosevelt Memorial (Map-case 2)
    - Wisconsin
      - Kenosha
        - First National Bank (Map-case 2)
    - Unidentified (Map-case 2)
    - Unidentified Library (Box 10)